One of the things that really interests
me in robotics is creating a synthetic
brain using physical synthetic neurons.
So, yeah, of course we can make an AI
that mimic the brain. We talked about a
whole brain simulation for a fly, which
is essentially uploading a fly, and
that's another conversation. But, if you
can make neurons, you can make a nervous
system. If you can make a nervous
system, you can make a brain. The trick
is getting them to respond to the same
neurochemical transmitters that our
brains respond to. They can be made so
similar to our own neurons, they can be
interfaced with our own neurons, and
that's really great for say prosthetics,
but it also means you could make a
standalone robot capable of learning.
Now, there are a few different goals to
emulating a brain, the first of which
would of course be artificial
intelligence. You want to create
something that is truly intelligent and
could look a lot like our own brains.
The research development area, so you
want to have a model that you can work
on that reliably acts like a human
brain. Now, these guys crafted synthetic
neurons and turn them into a sort of
artificial intelligence is capable of
learning. This is a huge step from using
synthetic neurons that then report back
to a home computer who then makes
decisions. The neurons themselves are
going to be the substrate of
intelligence. Now, you will see
synthetic neurons referred to a lot as
memristors. They're kind of the same
idea. A transistor is something that can
control the current that passes through
it. A memristor, on the other hand, is a
transistor that has been physically
changed when that current passes through
it, and a synthetic neuron could have a
lot of different characteristics. I've
mentioned that some can react to
dopamine and epinephrine and other
neurotransmitters.
One of the things you're going to have
to accomplish in order to create
something intelligent is going to be
responding to some of those
neurotransmitters in a goal-directed
manner. One of the ways that you can
accomplish that is with the classic
actor-critic network. The actor is going
to be in charge of taking an action, and
the critic is involved in evaluating
that action. It's not actually too
dissimilar from the concept of
metacognition, meaning you have
something that's capable of doing the
task, and then you have to evaluate if
it was a good choice or not. They use
the system to train an agent, which is
represented up there as a mouse, walk
through a maze and find the reward.
This, of course, does need to be
evaluated by a computer. It's not a
robot walking around in a little body,
at least not yet.
Creating goal-directed synthetic
intelligences that change their behavior
based on the physical properties of
their synthetic neurons is something
that a lot of groups are trying to do
right now. Now, one big problem is that
we don't know how a synthetic being
would respond to want. We don't know
what kind of will it would have. For us,
when our homeostasis is a little off, we
might want to go eat food or drink
water. But, for a synthetic being, we
might have to train them to respond
positively to neurotransmitters.
Fortunately, it does seem likely that
the goal of all organized systems is to
maintain order. Another question is that
if we create something that is actually
intelligent, what would it think of us?
Would it try to gain freedom? After all,
the goal of all life is to live for as
long as you can and to raise offspring
that can also live to have more
offspring. If this wasn't the case,
evolution wouldn't happen. But, if we
really wanted to create something that
is truly alive, it would also have to be
capable of reproduction.
This kind of research really makes me
question what it means to be alive, what
it means to be intelligent, what it
means to have will or want, and whether
or not something that we made
synthetically
could have want. And I would say, yeah,
I think it could.
This field is really at the very, very
start, though it's really fascinating to
see all the directions that it's going
in. And, of course, as we know, we can
skip the middleman and then just put
actual tiny lab-grown brains in charge
of robots. That is also an option, and
they respond to dopamine in a different
way, one that's more familiar to us.
I would like to pose a question. Let's
say we actually accomplished it. We
created a synthetic human brain that is
indistinguishable from how our own brain
functions, either emulated on a computer
or in a physical state in a robot with
synthetic neurons crafted into a brain.
If If is indistinguishable from a human,
the spiking patterns of their neurons or
the behaviors they might have, how do we
know if it's having an experience or
we're just simulating one? At what point
would we consider experimentation to be
unethical? At what point would we
consider giving them rights or would us
as human indeed just continue to say
that it's not real. I don't care what
you say, it's not actually having an
experience, it just thinks it's having
one. These are things that keep me up at
night and I would love to hear what
other people have to say about it
because it may be a future that we have
to consider.